Preliminary Inventory to the United Automobile, Aerospace and Agricultural Implement Workers of America, Local 2320 (National Organization of Legal Service Workers), Legal Services Staff Association Records WAG.163
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
United Automobile, Aerospace and Agricultural Implement Workers of America, Local 2320 (National Organization of Legal Service Workers), Legal Services Staff Association Records
1973-2009
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
United Automobile, Aerospace and Agricultural Implement Workers of America. Local 2320 (National Organization of Legal Service Workers). Legal Services Staff Association
WAG.163
49 Linear Feet (49 boxes)
1 websites in 1 archived website.
Representing workers in the legal profession, the Legal Services Staff Association (LSSA) is part of the National Organization of Legal Services Workers (NOLSW), which itself is Local 2320 of the United Automobile Workers of America (UAW). The membership of LSSA consists of employees of Legal Services NYC (formerly Community Action for Legal Services) and MFY Legal Services, which provide free legal assistance to people in New York City. The collection consists of the records of UAW, Local 2320, LSSA in the form of correspondence, board meeting records (including minutes), as well as negotiation, organizing, legal, financial, and general administrative files.
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists of the records of UAW, Local 2320, LSSA in the form of correspondence, board meeting records (including minutes), as well as negotiation, organizing, legal, financial, and general administrative files.
Historical/Biographical Note
Representing workers in the legal profession, the Legal Services Staff Association (LSSA) is part of the National Organization of Legal Services Workers (NOLSW), which itself is Local 2320 of the United Automobile Workers of America (UAW). The membership of LSSA consists of employees of Legal Services NYC (formerly Community Action for Legal Services) and MFY Legal Services, which provide free legal assistance to people in New York City.
LSSA was organized in New York City in 1972, one of the first unions in the legal profession. It played a critical role in the 1978 formation of NOLSW. In 1980, NOLSW affiliated with District 65 during the period in which District 65 itself affiliated with the UAW. When District 65 collapsed in the mid-1990s, NOLSW became UAW Local 2320.
Today, LSSA's 270 members make it the largest unit in NOLSW. Not surprisingly, given its membership of employees in legal services organizations, LSSA is a highly active and visible unit within both NOLSW and the UAW.
Arrangement
This collection is unprocessed.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials found in repository; provenance is unknown. The accession number associated with this collection is 1950.278.
http://nolsw.org/ was initially selected by curators and captured through the use of The California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service in 2009 as part of Labor Unions and Organizations (U.S.) Web Archive. In 2015, this website was migrated to Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. In 2019, http://nolsw.org/index.cfm?zone=/unionactive/past_articles.cfm&localnum=, http://www.nolsw.org/index.cfm?zone=/unionactive/officers.cfm, http://www.nolsw.org/index.cfm?zone=/unionactive/office_locations.cfm, and http://www.nolsw.org/index.cfm?zone=/unionactive/gallery_view.cfm was added to better capture the website. The accession number associated with this website is 2020.007.
Appraisal
Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.
If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.
If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the special.collections@nyu.edu.
Please include the following in your notice: Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature. Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.
Legal services -- New York (State) -- New York.; Lawyers -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York.; Web sites.; MFY Legal Services (New York, N.Y.); Legal Services NYC; Community Action for Legal Services; United Automobile Workers of America. Local 2320 (National Organization of Legal Service Workers); United Automobile, Aerospace and Agricultural Implement Workers of America. Local 2320 (National Organization of Legal Service Workers). Legal Services Staff Association
- Inventory
  - Agenda and Meeting Minutes of Delegates (1975 - 1981), Membership Correspondence, Strategy Committee, Job Announcements, Legal Correspondence, Financial Statements, Organizational Materials, 1975-1985 (Box 1)
  - Field Reports, Correspondence, Publications, Union and Delegate Materials, Grievances, Handwritten Notes, Questionnaires, NLRB Files, Legal Memoranda, 1974-1986 (Box 2)
  - LSSA Election Proceedings, Legal Files: Briefs and Memoranda, Contracts, Financial Contracts and Statistics, Reports on Financial Statements, Community Reports, 1966-1975 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence and Administrative Materials, Membership Minutes, Employee Certification, Announcements, Contract Arbitrators Aways, Contract-Challenged Employees, Panel Evidence, Legal Briefs and Memoranda, 1973-1974 (Box 4)
  - Legal Briefs: DC Certification LSC, Certification and Recognition Files, LSC Organization Files, Correspondence, Notes, Memorandum, Petitioner Exhibits, Salary Descriptions, 1983 (Box 5)
  - Legal Briefs: DC Unorg and Cert -- LSC, Trial Material, 1983 (Box 6)
  - Legal, Member, and Strategy Surveys, Handwritten Notes, Client Outreach, Reports, Local Newspapers for the Media Committee, Registration Forms, 1990-1991 (Box 7)
  - Budget and Financial Reports, Questionaire, Committee Reports and Materials, Contract drafts, Management Demands, Handwritten Notes, Memoranda to Staff (LSSA), Board Members Matrix, 1977-1985 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, Strike Material, Negotiation Files, Mailing Lists, Fliers, Handwritten Notes, Budgetary Charts, 1990-1993 (Box 9)
  - NLRB Briefs, Negotiation Materials, Contract and Questionaires, Safety and Health Reports, Salary Charts, Demonstration Files, Press Releases, Journal Advertisements, Workers' Committee, Affirmative Action Committee, 1981-1986 (Box 10)
  - Memoranda, Charts, LSC Fundraising, Applications, Reviews and Approvals, Union Notes, CALS Budget, Program Evaluations, Member Lists, MFY, Legal Services for the Elderly, Salary Reports, Questionaires, 1985-1986 (Box 11)
  - Legal Briefs, Memoranda, and Correspondence: Folger Library Material, DC Unorg, Defenders, Multi-national Monitor Press, National Law Journal, Rural Health Reports, Child Services, Organizational Directories, Publishing Information: Graphic Artists' Guild, 1984 (Box 12)
  - OR Law Suit and Appeal: Papers & Pleadings -- Multi-organizational, Affidavits, Miscellaneous Research, Union Files, Portland Papers, 1985-1990 (Box 13)
  - LSSA Negotiations, Draft of Demands, Summary of Demands, Contract Costs, Letter and Leaflets, Childcare Files, Handwritten Notes, Artwork, VDT Information, Legal Correspondence and Reports, 1988 (Box 14)
  - Coalitional and Organization Memoranda, Handwritten Notes and Letters, Special Reports and Mailings, Newsletters, Correspondence, Materials Related to Procedural Policy and Jt. Union Effort for Legal Services, Wharton Papers, Save Legal Services Files, LSC Brief, 1981-1985 (Box 15)
  - Newsletters, Handwritten Notes, Committee Files, Correspondence and Published Messages, Solidarity Organizations -- Letters and Donors, Demonstration Files, Affiliation Materials, Bronx Legal Services, Insurance Reports, LSC Resolutions, Funding Materials, Individual Files, Program Checklists, 1979-1982 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, Handwritten Notes, Questionaires, Reports: Salary for Legal Workers, Membership, Executive Counsel Summaries, Project Directors--Bronx, Certification Litigation, LSSA Delegation and Meeting Minutes, Executive Committee Agenda, Demonstration Files and Organization, Certification - Litigation Notes, 1973-1977 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, Memoranda, Collective Bargaining Agreements, LSSA Job Openings, Labor Bibliography, LSC Regulations, Personnel Action Forms, Reorgranization and Transition Offices, Budgetary Paperwork, 1988-1992 (Box 18)
  - LSSA Negotiation Files, Correspondence, Support Staff Resolutions, Contact Information for Elected Officials, Memoranda, Reports, Overviews for Legal Services, Phone Trees, Handwritten Notes, Charts, 1990-1991 (Box 19)
  - Memoranda, Letters to the Public, Correspondence, Salary Comparison Charts, CBA -- Committee Files, Publicity and Newspaper Files, Political Correspondence, Support Data, Strike Files -- Manual, Data, and Background -- Labor Outreach, Ethics Committee, Strike Funds, Labor Newspapers, Press, Radio and Contacts, Statements of Support from Politicians, 1979 (Box 20)
  - Loan Reports, Legal Correspondence, NAPIL Materials, Student Loan Forgiveness, LSC Appropriations, OH (Unorg) Pro Seniors, National Youth Law Services, Finance and Deficit Reduction, Reports, Charts, and Notes, National Organization of Legal Service Workers -- Folder with Component Paperwork, Convention Organizing, 1990-1992 (Box 21)
  - National Lawyer's Guild Fax and Materials, Mailing, Phone Calls, BETI, Bargaining, Insurance Information, Staff Notes (Handwritten), Immigration Project, State Files, 1990-1991 (Box 22)
  - Strikes, Mailing Lists, Phone Trees, Legal Correspondence, Handwritten Notes, Reports, Leaflets, 1991 (Box 23)
  - Insurance Files -- Theft, Liability, LSSA Material -- Job Announcements, Credit Union Deposits, Budget Crisis, CALS Board Minutes, Board of Directors Matrix, CALS Training Announcements, Affiliation Recognition, Conventions, Committees, Staff Meeting Minutes, CALS Restructuring, 1978-1985 (Box 24)
  - Organizing Drive, Il, Gd, DC, GHA -- Binder: Group Health Association Personnel Policies, 1979-1984 (Box 25)
  - Tribunals: Individual Files, Exhibits, Union, Union Hearings, Membership List, SCAB Hearings, Finds, LSSA Correspondence, Hearing Proceedings, 1979 (Box 26)
  - Dorkin Files: Union Activity, Job Announcements, Salaries, Correspondence, Demands and Offers, Action Plans, Budgetary Files, Handwritten Notes, 1980-1986 (Box 27)
  - CSDF Files, Budget Projections, CALS Restructuring, Support Centers, CALS Support, Bronx Evaluation, Caseload States by Project, Committee Files, Contract Questionaires, Negotiation Notes, 1981-1986 (Box 28)
  - PRS Northwest Mississippi, NMRLS United League Tour, Leaflets and Literature, Flyers, Press, Newspaper Clippings and Newsletters, Handwritten Notes, Correspondence, Miscellaneous and Support Files, 1978-1979 (Box 29)
  - Lawsuit and LSC Personnel Files, Grant Conditions, Houseman Materials, Refunding Application, Labor Law Preemption, Affidavits & Exhibits Union, LSC Materials, 1990 (Box 30)
  - CALS Restructuring Files, Questionaires, CALS Board and Budget Meetings, Resolution Management, Manhattan Legal Services, Funding and Trust Fund Files, Contract Votes, Membership Meetings, and Fact Sheets, Correspondence and Program Committee, 1982-1984 (Box 31)
  - Legal Transcripts: Community Action for Legal Services Employer and Legal Services Staff Association, 1984-1985 (Box 32)
  - Agenda and Meeting Minutes: 1980 - 1981, Correspondence, Handwritten Notes, Filings, Membership Mailings, Newsletters and old copies of LSSA News, Directories, Member Addresses, Benefits, Insurance, and Legal Services Files, Graphics and Logos, 1977-1985 (Box 33)
  - Minutes from the Board of Directors Meeting, Legal Transcripts: Community Action for Legal Services Inc. and Legal Services Staff Association; National Organization of Legal Service Workers, et. al., 1981-1986 (Box 34)
  - Negotiation Materials and Demands, LSSA NLRB Changes, Contract Demands, Contract Drafts across different Stages, Correspondence, Settlement and Settlement Changes, Demand Withdrawals, CBA Files, LSSA Meetings and Demands, LSSA Unit Clarification Petition, 1976-1979 (Box 35)
  - Transcripts of Legal Services Corporation Board of Directors Meeting, Audit and Accumulation Meeting Transcripts, Financial Statements, Memoranda, 1983-1986 (Box 36)
  - Individual Files and Project Development for Legal Services, Political Acciont Questionaires, Pension Plans, VDT Clippings, Correspondence, Action Press, Scientific Literature on Asbestos, Delegates Mailings, Dues Referendum, Announcements, Fliers and Leaflets, Meeting Notices, Betterment Fees, Salary Materials, CALS Management Evaluation, 1987-1992 (Box 37)
  - LSC Board Meetings (1987 & 1988), Board of Directors Operation and Regulation Meetings, Memoranda and Reports, Agendas, Handwritten Notes, Correspondence, Mailing Lists, 1987-1990 (Box 38)
  - Public Defender Conference Materials, Defenders Incorporated, Notes, Documents, Mailings, Literature, Correspondence, Newspaper Clippings, 1978-1984 (Box 39)
  - Organization Files: CALS Restructuring Proposal, Budgetary Materials, South African Conference, Board Composition of CALS, Audit Files, Bugets, Community Board Meeting Files and Correspondence, Allocations, New Member Materials, LSSA Holiday Party Materials, Retrenchment, Training, Post-Office Material, Temporary Employee Files, Leaftlets, Handwritten Notes, Newsletters, 1981-1984 (Box 40)
  - Newsletters: Prints, Drafts, and Notes, Parties and Events, Picnics, Outings, Holidays, Legal Analysis, Payroll changes and administration, Retroactive Pay, Staff Development, Dues, Education Fund, 1979-1986 (Box 41)
  - Organizing Drive Materials, LSE Individual Employee Fines, Testimonies, Bookeeping, Correspondence, Finance, Grievances, NY (Unorg), NOWLDEF, Statements and Reports, Newspaper Clippings, Fliers, Pamphlets, Individual Files, Handwritten Notes, 1980-1983 (Box 42)
  - Personnel Files, Individual Correspondence, Overtime Grievances, Asbestos Litigation, CALS files, Notes, Mailings, Paralegal Studies, 1981-1990 (Box 43)
  - Disbursements, Hardship Fund Requests, Correspondence, Handwritten Notes, Checks and Account Payments, Picket Cards, Joint Contracts, Expenses, Handwritten Notes, 1990 (Box 44)
  - Meeting Minutes and Staff Administration Contracts, Briefs and Audits, CCR Staff Meeting Minutes, Personnel Committee Files, CCR Board Meeting Files, Salary Committee Files, Legal Correspondence, Pamphlets, and Dockets, 1992-1994 (Box 45)
  - Legal Transcripts, Respondent-Employer's Post-Hearing Brief: Communit Action for Legal Services, Inc. and Legal Services Staff Association District 65, United Auto Workers, 1984 (Box 46)
  - State Legal Workers and TLSU Files, Expenses Reimbursement, Correspondences, Briefs and Legal Motions, Memoranda, Budget, 1986-1989 (Box 47)
  - CALS Board Minutes, Budget Modifications, Fundraising Attempts and Labor Negotiations, Dues and Dues check-off, Correspondence-General, Fundraising, Political Activity Rules and Regulations, NLADA, Contract Articles in LSC, Evaluations, CALS Financial Statements and Records, Board Minutes, 1975-1976 (Box 48)
  - Handwritten Notes, Correspondence, Union - LSSA Delegates and Executive Board, History, Firings, Delagates Training, Officers, Executive Council Minutes, CALS Regional Evalution, Support Files, Funding by City Counsel, CALS Executive Council Minutes, Log Sheets, Fundraising, CALS Restructuring, Pamphlets, Leaflets, and Newsletters, Reports and Memoranda, 1981-1986 (Box 49)
- Archived Website, January 2009-ongoing; 1 websites in one archived website.
  Scope and Content Note
  The National Organization of Legal Services Workers (NOLSW), UAW Local 2320, represents the majority of those who work in federally-funded legal services programs across the United States. The local also represents workers in other types of law offices, various human services programs and other agencies. The website includes news listings, strike listings, meeting information, gallery of images, office locations, lists of union officers, and other information.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
  Accruals
  New site crawls are accrued semiannually.
  Appraisal
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of nolsw.org, nolsw.org/index.cfm?zone=/unionactive/past_articles.cfm&localnum=, nolsw.org/index.cfm?zone=/unionactive/officers.cfm, nolsw.org/index.cfm?zone=/unionactive/office_locations.cfm, and nolsw.org/index.cfm?zone=/unionactive/gallery_view.cfm in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.